<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yann Hamon</title>
    <link>https://yann.mandragor.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yann Hamon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yann.mandragor.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solving the CDN post-purge thundering herd problem: The PurgeGroup pattern</title>
      <link>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/purge-group-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/purge-group-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Running a full purge of a CDN&amp;rsquo;s cache can be a risky endeavour. Since a CDN usually heavily caches requests, the origin only receives a fraction of all customers&#39; traffic.
For a short amount of time following a purge operation, the CDN&amp;rsquo;s cache is empty and all incoming requests are forwarded to the origin. If the cache/hit ratio of the CDN is 98%, the number of requests hitting the origin immediately after the purge might be up to 50 times greater than usual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating greater reliability: CoreDNS-nodecache</title>
      <link>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/coredns-nodecache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/coredns-nodecache/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing issues in the Linux kernel’s UDP connection tracking have caused challenges with DNS, and bugs particularly affect DNS in Kubernetes in its default configuration; we saw elevated rates of DNS failures that seemed to increase with load on our clusters. Other developers have reported these problems in blog posts, such as Racy conntrack and DNS lookup timeouts and a reason for unexplained connection timeouts on Kubernetes/Docker. In these cases, a race condition in the kernel [&amp;hellip;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Kubernetes manifests validity &amp; compliance - a tooling overview</title>
      <link>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/manifests-validity-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/manifests-validity-compliance/</guid>
      <description>In an Infrastructure as code / GitOps world, testing that your Kubernetes configuration is correct, secure, and compliant to your company&amp;rsquo;s requirements &amp;amp; best practices is more important than ever. An increasingly large list of tools is there to help you - linters, validators, testing frameworks, admission controllers&amp;hellip; each working in subtly different ways.
To help you navigate these waters, I will present some of the most common tools for Kubernetes manifests validation &amp;amp; compliance testing, detail their use, limitations and provide some usage examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making S3 more resilient using Lambda@Edge</title>
      <link>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/making-s3-more-resilient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/making-s3-more-resilient/</guid>
      <description>[&amp;hellip;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-sourcing kube-secret-syncer: A Kubernetes operator to sync secrets from AWS Secrets Manager</title>
      <link>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/kube-secret-syncer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/external_publications/kube-secret-syncer/</guid>
      <description>We’re releasing the open source code for Kube-secret-syncer, a Kubernetes operator that syncs secrets from AWS Secrets Manager. This operator improves on existing projects by delivering sophisticated access control, templated fields and caching to reduce costs. For those familiar with the struggles that come from synching secrets between the two, we hope this comes as a welcome solution. [&amp;hellip;]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
