<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog posts on Yann Hamon</title><link>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog posts on Yann Hamon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The execution model of AWS Lambda@edge with Cloudfront's two- and three-tiered architecture</title><link>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/lambda-execution-model/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/lambda-execution-model/</guid><description>The introduction of Lambda@Edge in 2016/2017 was probably one of the most significant updates to AWS Cloudfront in the last decade. By enabling customers to run code directly in Cloudfront&amp;rsquo;s Point-Of-Presences (POPs), AWS was at the forefront of edge computing, leveraging countless use-cases, from simple header manipulation, to custom authentication workflows.
Lambda@Edge relies on a simple execution model that defines four different places to manipulate CloudFront request or response objects:</description></item><item><title>Solving the CDN post-purge thundering herd problem: The PurgeGroup pattern</title><link>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/purge-group-pattern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yann.mandragor.org/posts/purge-group-pattern/</guid><description>Purging a Content Delivery Network (CDN) cache can be a risky endeavour. Since a CDN usually heavily caches requests, the origin only receives a fraction of all customers' traffic.
For a short amount of time following a purge operation, the CDN cache is empty and all incoming requests are sent to the origin. If the cache hit ratio is usually around 98%, the number of requests hitting the origin immediately after the purge might be up to 50 times greater than usual.</description></item></channel></rss>